DIE ZWÖLFTE STUNDE - THE TWELFTH HOUR
NOSFERATU . A SYMPHONY OF HORROR .
After the novel Dracula by Bram Stoker .
Freely adapted by Henrik Galeen .
Direction : F. W. Murnau .
Costumes and Sets : Albin Grau .
Photography : F. A. Wagner .
Music : Hans Erdmann .
Cast :
Count Orlok : Max Schreck
Hutter : Gustav v. Wangenheim
Ellen , his wife : Greta Schroeder
Harding , a shipowner : G. H. Schnell
Ruth , his sister : Ruth Landshoff
Professor Sievers , the town doctor : Gustav Botz
Knock , a property agent : Alexander Granach
Professor Bulwer , a Paracelsian : John Gottowt
A Captain : Max Nemetz
1st Sailor : Wolfgang Heinz
2nd Sailor : Albert Venohr
1st Act .
Chronicle of the Great Death in Wisborg
anno Domini 1838 , by ...
NOSFERATU
Does this word not sound to you like the midnight cry of the Deathbird .
Take care in saying it ,
lest life 's images fade into shadows , and ghostly dreams rise from
your heart and nourish themselves on your blood .
Long have I contemplated the origin and recession
of the Great Death in my hometown of Wisborg .
Here is it 's story :
There lived in Wisborg Hutter and his young wife Ellen
Why did you kill them ... the lovely flowers ? !
Not so fast , my young friend ! No-one outruns his destiny .
There was also a property agent by the name of Knock -
the subject of all sorts of rumours .
One thing was certain : He paid his people well
Count Orlok - His Lordship ... from Transylvania ...
wishes to acquire a beautiful home in our little town ...
You could earn a nice bit of money
of course the price is a little effort ... some sweat
and perhaps ... a little blood ...
He wants a fine , deserted house ...
That house ... directly across from yours .
Offer him that one !
Travel quickly , travel well , my young friend ,
into the land of the spectres .
I 'm travelling far , far away
into the land of thieves and spectres .
So Hutter placed the anguished girl in the care of his friends ,
the rich shipowner Harding and his sister
Be at ease .
And young Hutter travelled many dusty roads ,
but at last the peaks of the Carpathlans
loomed before him .
The horses strained harder
Quickly ... something to eat -
I have to get to Count Orlok 's castle !
You shouldn 't go any further now : The Werewolf roams the woods .
Of Vampyres Gastlie Spirits , Bewitchments
and the Seven Deadlie Sins
From Belial 's seed sprang the vampyre NOSFERATU ,
who doth live and feed on the bloode of humankind -
Beyonde deliverance he doth dwell in gastlie caves ,
sepulchres and coffins , filled so with god-curst earth
from the fields of the Black Death
Of Vampyres Gastlie Spirits , Bewitchments
and the Seven Deadlie Sins
Onward ! The sun is setting !
Offer what you like ! We 're not going any further !
We won 't go on ! I  s frightening beyond the pass !
No sooner had Hutter stepped across the bridge ,
than the eerle visions he had often told me about
seized hold of him .
You have kept me waiting - waiting too long . -
Now it is nearly midnight . The servants are sleeping !
End of the 1st Act .
Nosferatu 2nd Act .
You have hurt yourself ... Precious blood !
Shouldn 't we like to sit together a bit , dear friend ?
It is a while still till Sunrise - and in the daytime I sleep ,
my dear fellow , I sleep the deepest of sleeps -
Just as the sun rose ,
the shadows of the night withdrew from Hutter as well
My dear ! My dearest !
Grieve not that thy beloved is so far away
I am plagued by mosquitoes .
I already have two bites on my throat ,
one quite near the other , on each side
One dreams so heavily in this desolate castle ,
but fear not .
The spectral evening light seemed to revive the shadows
of the castle once more
Your wife has a lovely neck ...
I shall buy the house ...
The fine , deserted house opposite yours ...
At night this same Nosferatu doth clutch his victim
and doth suck like hellish life-potion it 's blood .
Take heede that his shadow not encumber thee
like an incubus with gruesome dreams
At the same hour .
A doctor ... a doctor !
Harmless congestions of the blood .
The doctor related Ellen 's distress to me
as an unknown Illness .
I know , however , that her soul that night
caught the cry of the Deathbird -
Nosferatu was already spreading his wings . -
Yet with the morning light Hutter set out
to make sense of the horror of his nights . -
The raftsmen didn 't know what kind of unholy cargo
they were conveying through the dale .
End of the 2nd Act .
Nosferatu 3rd Act .
He was brought to the hospital yesterday by some farmers .
They said he must have fallen . He 's still feverish ...
Coffins -
Nosferatu was on his way . The danger for Wisborg drew nigh .
The Paracelslan Professor Bulwer ,
who at that time was studying the secrets of nature
and their deepest unifying principles ,
told me the following :
Earth - filled coffins were to be loaded
onto the double - masted ship , the Empusa
The vessel 's still set for sail tonight .
Bill of Lading : EMPUSA
Route : From GALAZ to WISBORG
Cargo : 6 crates of earth ( experimental purposes )
In those days , I should note , Prof. Bulwer was explaining
to his students the cruel habits of carnivorous plants .
They observed in horror nature 's mysterious ways .
Like a vampire - isn 't it ?
It seems that the approach of the strangler , Nosferatu ,
already compelled the property agent Knock
into his shadow .
The patient admitted yesterday is going mad ...
Blood is life ! Blood is life !
And this one here
a polyp with tentacles
transparent ... almost incorporeal
almost but a phantom ...
Spiders !
Ellen was often seen on the beach
within the solitude of the dunes .
Yearning for her beloved ,
her eyes scanned waves and distance alike .
My dear ! My dearest !
Grieve not that thy beloved is so far away
I am plagued by mosquitoes .
I already have two bites on my throat ,
one quite near the other , on each side
One dreams so heavily in this desolate castle ,
but fear not .
No I must go ... by the shortest route home !
PLAGUE . A plague epidemic has broken out
in Transylvania and the Black Sea ports
of Varna and Galaz .
All victims exhibit the same peculiar stigmata on the neck ,
the origin of which still puzzles the doctors .
The Dardanelles were closed to all ships
suspected of carrying the plague .
A sailor 's fallen ill below deck . He 's delirious .
It spread through the ship like an epidemic .
The first stricken sailor pulled the entire crew
after him into the dark grave of the waves .
In the light of the sinking sun ,
the captain and ship ' s mate
bid farewell to the last of their comrades .
I 'm going below ! If I 'm not back up in ten minutes ...
The ship of death had acquired its new captain .
End of the 3rd Act .
Nosferatu 4th Act .
It 's quite difficult to say how , despite his depleted strength ,
young Hutter succeeded in surmounting the obstacles
on his voyage home - - meanwhlle , Nosferatu 's
deadly breath swelled the sails of the ship ,
which flew on toward it 's destination with ghostly haste .
I must go to him . He 's coming !
The master is near ... The master is near !
Long have I pondered why Nosferatu was said
to have travelled with earth-filled coffins .
I found it recorded that vampyres
can only draw their shadowy strength
from the accursed earth
in which they were buried .
Thank God ... you 're safe ... All 's well now ...
Looked over everything ... Not a living soul on board .
Varna - 12 July
Crew - minus myself as captain : One helmsman , :
One ship 's mate , : Five sailors
Second day - 13 July one sailor ill with fever
Course : SSW Wind : NE
Third day - 14 July ship 's mate is babbling
claims strange passenger is below deck
Course : SE Wind : NE
Tenth day - 22 July
rats in ship 's hold danger of plague
Danger of plague ! Go home !
Shut all windows and doors !
PROCLAMATION
It is hereby decreed that the honourable magistrate
of this town forbids the populace to transport
the ill or plague-stricken to the hospital
lest the plague spread through the streets .
End of the 4th Act .
Nosferatu 5th Act .
Hutter made Ellen swear not to touch the book
which had frightened him with it 's visions . -
Yet she could not resist it 's bizarre attraction .
At night this same Nosferatu doth clutch his victim
and doth suck like hellish life-potion it 's blood .
Take heede that his shadow not encumber thee
like an incubus with gruesome dreams
Wherefore no other salvation is possible ,
but that a maiden wholly without sin
maketh the Vampyre forget the first crow of the cock .
Would that she give freely of her blood
This is what I see - each evening !
Fear lurked in every corner of the town .
Who was still well ? Who already ill ?
I 'll run over there quickly ... I 'll fetch Sievers ...
Wherefore no other salvation is possible ,
but that a maiden wholly without sin
maketh the Vampyre forget the first crow of the cock .
Would that she give freely of her blood
The panic-stricken town was looking for a victim :
It was Knock .
Someone saw him ! He ran outside !
He strangled the custodian ...
He strangled him ... the vampire !
I LOVE YOU
Bulwer ! Fetch Bulwer !
Knock has been captured !
The master ... the master !
The master ... is ... dead .
Witness the miracle on the heels of the truth :
At that very hour ,
the Great Death came to an end , and as if confronted
by the victorious radiance of the living sun ,
the shadow of the Deathbird was dispersed .
END .